Hey Sam, uh congratulations and uh
welcome to Chicago. Um what was your
pre-draft process like in terms of
interactions with the Chicago Bears?
>> Yeah. Uh I did a I did a formal
interview with him at at the the combine
and that was super cool. So I I uh I
knew Jim Dre because you know obviously
he played uh tight end at Stanford and
then you know he had come back for some
of our pro days. So I got to see him
again at the at the combine and that was
super cool. Um but yeah, I'm fired up. I
think I talked to him at the Senior Bowl
as well and you know I I uh you know I
didn't I didn't think that I was in the
cards for for the Bears but I'm I'm
freaking fired up.
>> Pat Finley.
>> Hey Sam, did I read this? Did you live
all over the world as a kid?
>> I did. I did. Yes, sir.
>> What was what was that like? And did you
have some awareness of what football was
uh even when that was going on or or not
really?
>> Yeah. I mean I I moved uh I lived in
Asia for four years. Indonesia and
Malaysia. Um, it was interesting. It was
different. Uh, you know, just kind of
being the odd one out. But my I mean my
my dad played football at Duke. Uh, my
grandpa played in the NFL for 9 years
and his brother played for 13 years. Um,
my uncle played, you know, their their
dad both played. Um, so it's uh,
football's, you know, in my blood and,
you know, that's a big part of who I am
and I always knew it was something I was
going to do.
>> Dion,
>> congratulations. We're excited that
you're here. Um, what do you think you
can bring to a tight end room that
already includes a Cole KT and a Coulson
Lovelin, versatile guys, and and you
obviously bring that as well.
>> Yeah, first of all, um, I'm super fired
up to be a part of, you know, what is an
incredible tight end room. Like, those
are guys that I can learn from. Um, guys
that have been in the league for, you
know, one plus years, you know, they're
veterans and there's a lot I can learn
from them. And, you know, great tight
end coach as well. and, you know,
somebody that's that's played um in the
league and, you know, has been coaching
for for 10 plus years. Um, but yeah, I
mean, I'm I'm I bring a physical
presence to, you know, the the field
when I'm when I'm on it. And I want to
make an impact, you know, at at every,
you know, in every possible aspect of
the game. And, you know, obviously as a
rookie coming in, like I'm going to be
playing a lot of special teams and I
want to make an impact doing that. Um, I
think in the run game I can, you know,
be a huge value and that's something
that I pride myself in a lot is, you
know, my blocking and ability to to kind
of get on people and and wear them down
throughout the game.
>> Adam,
>> Sam, your great uncle was Merlin Olsson,
right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> How familiar are you with his story?
What did you hear about him? What did
you know?
>> Yeah, very familiar. Um, you know,
played in the league for I believe it
was 14 years. Um, and then my my
grandpa's Phil Olson, they played on the
Rams together for seven years. But, um,
you know, Merlin Olsen, absolute legend,
Fearsome Forsome, LA Rams, uh, Hall of
Famer, and then, you know, my my grandpa
got to be got to be a part of that as
well, and he was here with me tonight.
Um, um, I I knew my grandpa Merlin. He
passed away when I was about six years
old. Um, he had, uh, cancer from
asbestous, but, um, you know, he he was
a great man and, um, I look up to him
and my grandpa a lot. um making this
transition.
>> Kevin,
>> hey Sam, congratulations. U saw you
you've uh in your travels you played a
lot of rugby. Um curious how that's
helped you uh on the football field.
>> Yeah, I think I think just playing a you
know physical sport when you're young
helps build toughness. Obviously I have
my neighbors that you know I wrestle
with and um you know bang around with
but uh you know playing playing kind of
an organized physical sport when I was
in you know elementary middle school
kind of helps with you know form
tackling general physicality
um you know I think it definitely
translated real well to football and you
know kind of contact balance
>> and how would you describe um your
experience on special teams and is that
an area that you kind of um take some
pride in?
>> Absolutely. Yes sir. I mean towards
towards the end of my career at Stanford
I didn't play a whole lot of special
teams truthfully just I was on the field
uh constantly on offense but you know my
my freshman year I came in I played the
second most special team snaps in the
country and um special teams is you know
something that I'm going to take a lot
of pride in and you know that's that's
that's a huge part of the game that you
know doesn't get talked about a lot and
I think that's you know just another way
that I can bring value to this team.
Last one, Larry.
>> Kind of stole my thunder there, but I
was going to ask you about blocking and
uh obviously everybody always talks
about how many receptions a tight end
has, but how much pride do you take in
blocking and knowing that you're really
not going to get a lot of credit
publicly for stuff like that?
>> I I love blocking. Um, you know, the O
linemen are some of my favorite people
on the team, and I love, you know,
getting in the trench with them and
getting dirty and, you know, that's
that's a huge part of my game that that
I take so much pride in. And um you know
I I never want to let that go. Um you
know no matter how many catches you have
you you always got to come back to your
roots. I feel like, you know, blocking
is, you know, the gritty, you know,
roots part of football that, you know, I
feel like, you know, that's how you play
the game the right way is, you know,
putting your head down when you know
you're not going to get credit for it
and, you know, taking one for the name.